rivier.edu 2018-01-07

# Rivier University E-commerce Information Usage Statement The security and privacy of your e-commerce transactions at Rivier University are of the utmost importance to us. Only information required to conduct business is utilized by Rivier University. No information is sold or otherwise provided to third parties from Rivier University or affiliated vendor’s Web sites except as expressly stated, or as required by law. This statement applies to all linked Rivier University Web pages. Please be sure to check other sites for their policies. 1.

                                            Rivier University
                               E-commerce Information Usage Statement
The security and privacy of your e-commerce transactions at Rivier University are of the utmost
importance to us. Only information required to conduct business is utilized by Rivier University. No
information is sold or otherwise provided to third parties from Rivier University or affiliated
vendor’s Web sites except as expressly stated, or as required by law. This statement applies to all
linked Rivier University Web pages. Please be sure to check other sites for their policies.
     1. Introduction
     2. Information We Collect
     3. Our Use and Disclosure of Information
     4. Information Security
     5. Links to Other Web Sites
     6. Contacting Us
1. Introduction
The ability to make payments electronically to Rivier University on the Web is provided as a
convenience for the entire Rivier University community. To insure transactions are appropriately
assigned and to reduce the risk of fraud Rivier University must collect sufficient information to
positively identify users. This Statement describes the information we collect, how it is utilized and
protected. Rivier University respects the privacy of your personally identifiable information. We will
not sell or rent your personally identifiable information. However, as described in more detail in
Section 3 below, there are limited circumstances in which some of your information will be by
necessity, under strict restrictions, shared with third parties.
By using this site, you signify that you understand how the privacy and security of your personal
information is protected and how your personal information will be used. We reserve the right, at
our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this statement at any time. Your
continued use of Rivier University e-commerce sites following the posting of any changes signifies
that you acknowledge and accept those changes. If you have any questions or concerns, please
contact one of the following offices at Rivier University:
The Office of the Registrar: asktheregistrar@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8213
The Office of Information Technology: Help Line at ITSupport@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8469
The Business Office: busoffice@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8214
2. Information We Collect
Network Information
Information collected automatically is analyzed to help us understand how you use our web
services and how we can improve our site to better meet your needs. Examples of data that may be
collected include:
                                                    1

IP Address
Type of browser and operating system used to access our site
Date and time the user accessed our site
Information regarding which pages users’ access or visit
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this site may
monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or
otherwise cause damage. If security monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal
activity, system personnel may provide the results of such monitoring to appropriate officials.
Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and
may be punishable under the state law and federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996.
Email Information
If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally
identifying information, we will only use the personally identifiable information to respond to your
request and analyze trends. We may redirect your message to a governmental agency or person
who is in a better position to answer your question.
Required Information
In order to make payments all of the payment information is transferred to SALLIE MAE. Credit card
and bank information will not be collected or stored by Rivier University. This information is
necessary for us to process transactions, to protect you against credit card fraud, and to contact
you should the need arise in administering your account.
Transactional Information
When you make a payment to Rivier University we ask you to provide information related to each
transaction such as the amount of the payment. Information provided by the user is the data
needed to successfully complete a Web transaction. This information may be retained by Rivier
University to insure the transaction has been properly assigned.
Our Use of "Cookies"
"Cookies" are small files of data that we send to your computer to allow us to recognize you as an
authenticated user. We send a "session cookie" to your computer when you log in to your Web
account. These cookies allow us to recognize you if you visit multiple pages in our site during the
same session without requiring you to log on for each page. Once you log out or close your
browser, these session cookies expire and no longer have any effect. Our cookie files are encoded
so that your information can only be interpreted by Rivier University Web applications.
3. Our Use and Disclosure of Information
Internal Uses
We use the information we collect about you in order 1) to provide our services and process your
transactions and 2) to provide customer service. Specifically, we use your information to help you
complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, to update you on service and benefits, and to
personalize our web sites for you. We give access to personally identifiable information about our
users only to those Rivier University employees who need to know that information in order to
provide products or services to you.
                                                   2

Disclosure to Other Users
Except as noted above for need to know employees, no other users can view your personal data.
Disclosure to Third Parties
Rivier University will not sell, rent, or lease your personally identifiable information to others. Rivier
University will not share any of your personally identifiable information with third parties except in
the limited circumstances described below, or with your express permission (and to employees as
described above), or to comply with applicable law. These third parties are limited by law or by
contract from using the information for secondary purposes beyond the purposes for which the
information is shared.
     1. We share information with organizations that help us process the transactions you request
         and protect our customers' transactions from fraud, such as sharing your credit card
         number with a service that screens for lost and stolen card numbers.
     2. We disclose the information we collect, as described above, to organizations that perform
         services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with which we have joint service
         agreements i.e. a credit card clearing house. These organizations are subject to
         confidentiality and privacy policies and other legal restrictions that prohibit using the
         information except to provide the specified related services, unless you have affirmatively
         agreed or given your prior permission for other uses. We disclose information that we in
         good faith believe is appropriate to cooperate in investigations of fraud or other illegal
         activity, or to conduct investigations of violations of our Information Technology Computer
         Use Policy.
     3. We disclose information in response to a subpoena, warrant, court order, levy, attachment,
         order of a court-appointed receiver or other comparable legal process, including subpoenas
         from private parties in a civil action.
     4. We disclose information to your agent or legal representative (such as the holder of a
         power of attorney that you grant, or a guardian appointed for you).
     5. We share information with third parties, in compliance with the Federal Family Educational
         Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA).
Internet Address Information
We use IP addresses, browser types, and access times to analyze trends, administer the site,
improve site performance, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, and to
conduct investigations on fraud, illegal activity, and other violations of our Information Technology
Computer Use Policy.
4. Information Security
Rivier University is committed to handling your information with high standards of information
security and in compliance with the Rivier University Information Technology Computer Use Policy.
While no computing environment is 100% secure, we take appropriate precautions to protect the
                                                      3

user's information. When a user submits sensitive information via the Web, that information is
protected both online and off-line.
5. Links to Other Web Sites
Our Web sites contain links to non-Rivier University sites not associated with e-commerce. Please
be aware that Rivier University is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. The
user is encouraged to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of
each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement
applies solely to information collected by Rivier University e-commerce access pages. Other Rivier
University Web sites, as well as non-Rivier University Web sites, may have their own privacy
statement which should be reviewed.
6. Contacting Us
If you have questions about our web site or concerns regarding privacy, please contact one of the
following offices at Rivier University:
The Office of the Registrar: asktheregistrar@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8213
The Office of Information Technology: Help Line at ITSupport@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8469
The Business Office: busoffice@rivier.edu – (603) 897-8214
                                                   4
